Pachter, Henry M.; Papers ger071
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Published Newspaper Articles, 1932-1986; Undated; 6
  - Anti-Communism, 1949-1962 (Box 4 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 56)
  - Art, the Arts, 1950-1973 (Box 4 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 57)
  - Asia, SEATO, ANZUS, Indonesia, Australia, Philippines, 1951-1971 (Box 4 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 58)
  - Atomic Energy (International), 1953-1969 (Box 4 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 59)
  - Atomic Energy (National)., 1950-1958 (Box 4 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 60)
  - Atomic Non-Proliferation Treaty, 1966-1968 (Box 4 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 61)
  - Atomic Tests, 1961-1963 (Box 4 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 62)
  - Austria, 1955-1962 (Box 4 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 63)
  - Automation, 1951-1971 (Box 4 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 64)
  - Automobile, 1948-1970 (Box 4 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 65)
  - Aviation, 1950-1964 (Box 4 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 66)
  - Big Deal, 1949-1966 (Box 4 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 67)
  - Biographies, A – K, 1950-1976 (Box 4 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 68)
  - Biographies, L – Z., 1950-1976 (Box 4 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 69)
  - Bomb, 1949-1970 (Box 4 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 70)
  - Budget., 1949-1960 (Box 4 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 71)
  - Business Administration, 1960 (Box 4 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 72)
  - Canada, 1951-1970 (Box 4 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 73)
  - Chemical Industry, 1949-1962 (Box 4 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 74)
  - China, 1949-1972 (Box 4 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 75)
  - Cities, 1968 (Box 4 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 76)
  - Civil Liberties, 1949-1977 (Box 4 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 77)
  - Climate, Water, Conservation, 1951-1971 (Box 4 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 78)
  - Colonies, Satellites, Colonialism, 1952-1974 (Box 4 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 79)
  - Commerce, Sales, Advertising, Trade, 1949-1963 (Box 4 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 80)
  - Communications, 1957-1964 (Box 4 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 81)
  - Communism, 1949-1972 (Box 4 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 82)
  - Congress, 1949-1979 (Box 4 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 83)
  - Conservatism, 1952-1971 (Box 4 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 84)
  - Constitution, 1949-1970 (Box 4 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 85)
  - Consumer Goods, Consumer Credits, Services, Savings, 1948-1966 (Box 5 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 1)
  - Corporations, 1950-1975 (Box 5 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 2)
  - Cotton, Wool, 1950-1959 (Box 5 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 3)
  - The Country, 1948-1971 (Box 5 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 4)
  - Crime and Courts, 1949-1974 (Box 5 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 5)
  - Cuba, 1952-1966 (Box 5 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 6)
  - Defense, 1949-1959 (Box 5 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 7)
  - Defense, 1960-1972 (Box 5 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 8)
  - Defense Industries, 1951-1959 (Box 5 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 9)
  - Democrats, 1952-1973 (Box 5 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 10)
  - Disarmament, 1949-1970 (Box 5 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 11)
  - Displaced Persons, 1950-1971 (Box 5 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 12)
  - Economic Policy, 1948-1971 (Box 5 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 13)
  - Economy (Konjunktur), 1948-1956 (Box 5 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 14)
  - Economy (Konjunktur), 1957-1975 (Box 5 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 15)
  - Education, 1949-1975 (Box 5 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 16)
  - Eisenhower, 1949-1969 (Box 5 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 17)
  - Elections, 1948-1963 (Box 5 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 18)
  - Elections, 1964-1972 (Box 5 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 19)
  - England, 1951-1969 (Box 5 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 20)
  - Europe, 1949-1973 (Box 5 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 21)
  - Family, 1954-1971 (Box 5 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 22)
  - Farming, 1949-1966 (Box 5 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 23)
  - Food, 1948-1961 (Box 5 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 24)
  - Foreign Aid, Point Four, 1948-1971 (Box 5 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 25)
  - Foreign Economic Policy, 1962-1967 (Box 5 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 26)
  - Foreign Military Aid, 1967 (Box 5 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 27)
  - Foreign Policy (Dulles), 1948-1956 (Box 5 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 28)
  - Foreign Policy (Dulles), 1957-1961 (Box 6 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 1)
  - Foreign Policy (Kennedy; Johnson)., 1960-1968 (Box 6 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 2)
  - Foreign Policy (Nixon), 1968-1972 (Box 6 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 3)
  - Foreign Trade, 1949-1968 (Box 6 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 4)
  - Foundations, 1955-1963 (Box 6 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 5)
  - France, 1952-1970 (Box 6 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 6)
  - Free Enterprise, 1948-1969 (Box 6 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 7)
  - German Property, 1948-1965 (Box 6 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 8)
  - Germany, German Affairs, 1949-1956 (Box 6 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 9)
  - Germany, German Affairs, 1957-1960 (Box 6 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 10)
  - Germany, German Affairs, 1961-1965 (Box 6 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 11)
  - Germany, German Affairs, 1966-1976 (Box 6 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 12)
  - Goldwater, 1962-1968 (Box 6 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 13)
  - The Great Society, 1965 (Box 6 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 14)
  - Greece, 1964 (Box 6 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 15)
  - History, 1954-1963 (Box 6 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 16)
  - History, 1964-1978 (Box 6 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 17)
  - Housing, 1949-1972 (Box 6 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 18)
  - Humphrey, 1958-1968 (Box 6 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 19)
  - Immigration, 1950-1961 (Box 6 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 20)
  - Income, 1951-1963 (Box 6 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 21)
  - India, 1952-1973 (Box 6 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 22)
  - Indochina, 1954-1971 (Box 6 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 23)
  - International Court, 1960 (Box 6 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 24)
  - Investments, 1952-1962 (Box 6 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 25)
  - Japan, 1950-1969 (Box 6 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 26)
  - Jews, 1960-1980 (Box 6 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 27)
  - Johnson, 1949; 1963-1973 (Box 6 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 28)
  - Kennedy, 1957-1966 (Box 6 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 29)
  - Kennedy Assassination, 1963-1969 (Box 6 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 30)
  - The Kennedy's, 1962-1969 (Box 6 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 31)
  - Korea, 1950-1969 (Box 6 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 32)
  - Labor, Trade Unions, Social Services, 1948-1972 (Box 6 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 33)
  - Language, 1949-1971 (Box 6 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 34)
  - Latin America, 1950-1974 (Box 6 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 35)
  - Left, Liberals, Intellectuals, 1947-1967 (Box 6 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 36)
  - Literature, 1949-1974 (Box 6 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 37)
  - Literature (not by H.P.), 1949-1967 (Box 6 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 38)
  - Lobbies, 1965; 1971 (Box 6 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 39)
  - Managers, 1945-1964 (Box 7 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 1)
  - McCarthy, Eugene, 1967-1969 (Box 7 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 2)
  - McCarthy, Joseph, 1953-1954 (Box 7 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 3)
  - McNamara, Robert, 1960-1968 (Box 7 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 4)
  - Medacine, 1950-1967 (Box 7 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 5)
  - Melting Pot, 1951-1960 (Box 7 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 6)
  - Metals, Raw Materials, Diamonds, Steel, 1950-1965 (Box 7 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 7)
  - Middle East, India, Pakistan, Afghanistan, Persia, 1949-1969 (Box 7 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 8)
  - Minorities, 1950-1971 (Box 7 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous, 1950-1967 (Box 7 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 10)
  - Money, 1948-1968 (Box 7 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 11)
  - Monopoly, 1967 (Box 7 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 12)
  - Movies, 1949-1977 (Box 7 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 13)
  - Music, Dance, 1947-1971 (Box 7 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 14)
  - NATO, 1949-1970 (Box 7 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 15)
  - Near East, Palestine, 1951-1963 (Box 7 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 16)
  - Near East, Palestine, 1964-1973 (Box 7 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 17)
  - Negroes, 1964-1971 (Box 7 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 18)
  - Neo-Isolationism, 1965-1971 (Box 7 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 19)
  - Neutralism, Isolationism, Pacifism, 1965-1972 (Box 7 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 20)
  - New Left, 1963-1970 (Box 7 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 21)
  - New York City, 1949-1975 (Box 7 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 22)
  - Nixon, 1954-1974 (Box 7 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 23)
  - Oil, Coal, Gas, 1949-1974 (Box 7 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 24)
  - Pacifism, 1960-1973 (Box 7 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 25)
  - Panama, 1964-1968 (Box 7 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 26)
  - Peace Corps., 1966 (Box 7 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 27)
  - Peace Offensive, Big Four, 1951-1966 (Box 7 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 28)
  - Planning, 1963-1968 (Box 7 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 29)
  - Popular culture, 1949-1978 (Box 7 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 30)
  - Popular Trends, 1951-1965 (Box 7 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 31)
  - Poverty, 1963-1970 (Box 7 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 32)
  - Power, 1951-1958 (Box 7 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 33)
  - Press, 1949-1973 (Box 7 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 34)
  - Propaganda, Terror, Professional Warfare, 1949-1971 (Box 7 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 35)
  - Radioactivity, 1954-1963 (Box 7 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 36)
  - Railroads, Shipping, 1956-1966 (Box 7 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 37)
  - Reaction, 1948-1971 (Box 7 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 38)
  - Religion, 1949-1971 (Box 7 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 39)
  - Republicans, 1948-1968 (Box 8 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 1)
  - Rockefeller, Nelson, 1958-1968 (Box 8 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 2)
  - Russia, 1949-1959 (Box 8 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 3)
  - Russia, 1960-1973 (Box 8 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 4)
  - Science, 1951-1970 (Box 8 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 5)
  - Security, 1949-1971 (Box 8 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 6)
  - Share Holders, 1952-1957 (Box 8 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 7)
  - Small Business, 1949-1957 (Box 8 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 8)
  - Social Services, 1949-1975 (Box 8 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 9)
  - Socialism, 1949-1974 (Box 8 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 10)
  - Sociology, 1951-1968 (Box 8 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 11)
  - Space, 1952-1970 (Box 8 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 12)
  - Spain, 1932-1986 (Box 8 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 13)
  - Stevenson, Adlai, 1952-1965 (Box 8 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 14)
  - Stock Market, 1949-1963 (Box 8 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 15)
  - Summaries, 1948-1968 (Box 8 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 16)
  - Summit Conference, 1958-1967 (Box 8 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 17)
  - Taxes, 1954-1974 (Box 8 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 18)
  - Technique, Technology, Technocracy, 1951-1960 (Box 8 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 19)
  - Television, Radio, 1948-1968 (Box 8 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 20)
  - Textile, 1950-1960 (Box 8 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 21)
  - Theater, 1949-1972 (Box 8 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 22)
  - Truman, 1948-1971 (Box 8 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 23)
  - Trusts, 1949-1962 (Box 8 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 24)
  - Unemployment, 1949-1965 (Box 8 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 25)
  - United Nations, 1949-1957 (Box 8 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 26)
  - United Nations, 1958-1962 (Box 8 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 27)
  - United Nations, 1963-1965 (Box 8 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 28)
  - United Nations, 1966-1975 (Box 8 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 29)
  - Vatican, 1951-1970 (Box 8 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 30)
  - Vietnam, 1963-1966 (Box 8 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 31)
  - Vietnam, 1967-1973 (Box 8 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 32)
  - Vietnam peace talks, 1968-1973 (Box 8 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 33)
  - Weimar, 1965-1979 (Box 8 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 34)
  - Wheat, 1948-1963 (Box 8 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 35)
  - Women, 1950-1972 (Box 8 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 36)
  - Youth, 1956-1972 (Box 8 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 37)
  - Yugoslavia, 1951-1970; 1986 (Box 8 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 38)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1963-1964 (Box 8 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 39)
- Audio Tapes and Oversized Materials, 1984; Undated; 7
  The audio tapes include one reel-to-reel tape labeled Dissent, an interview with Pachter about Hannah Arendt, two cassettes (1 side each) of "Heinz Pachter – Gedenken I and II," and two cassettes (4 sides) of Pachter's Memoirs of an Exile. Memoirs of an Exile Tape 1 begins with Weimar on side one and side two features the end of Weimar/beginning of Spain. The second tape begins with France/Spain and finishes with Spain on the second side. The folders contain proofs of Socialism in History.
  - Socialism in History Page Proofs, 1984 (Box 9 (7-Audio Tapes and Oversized Materials), Folder 1-2)
  - Dissent, Undated (Reel 1)
  - Interview of Heinz Pachter about Hannah Arendt, Undated (Cassette 1)
  - Heinz Pachter.Gedenken I and II, Undated (Cassette 2-3)
  - Heinz Pachter reading a text on Bukarin, Undated (Cassette 4)
  - Heinz Pachter.Memoirs of an Exile, Undated (Cassette 5-6)